Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of History, honors theses
1958-2014
SC4-3960
Stanford University. Department of History.
31.75 Linear feet
Honors theses by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of History.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The theses were received via administrative transfers from the Department of History, and from the Hume Writing Center in 2011. Additional theses were received from David M. Kennedy in 2012.
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
The collection contains honors theses by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of History.
Access Terms
History; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Theses, pre-1991
  - Abernethy, Jonathan Sloan, Politics in the Streets: The Watts Rebellion of 1965, 1991; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Austin, James L., Jr., Red Men and White Eyes: Frontier American Attitudes Toward the Plains Indian and Their Effect on Indian-White Relations. (Box 1)
  - Babb, Stephen, The Motivation Behind the Emancipation Proclamation: Lincoln's Policy of Pragmatically Applied Morality, 1854-1865., May 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Beverly Lynn, Social Criticism and the American Fifties Novel., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Betts, Kenneth L., War within a War: Military Activities and Effects of Guerrillas in the Border States during the Civil War., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Biederman, Jerry H., The Locke - Leibniz Controversy. A Study in the Culture of the Enlightenment., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Borman, Lisa, Ethics and Aesthetics: Karl Kraus's Critique of the Language of Art and Politics. Winner of the James Birdsall Weter Prize, 1978/79., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Breck, George, The California Progressive and Alien Land Legislation: Reformer as Racist., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Burwell, Robert, Weaving the Entangling Web: The role of small and middle powers in the formation of the North Atlantic alliance, 1991; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Carter, Stephen L., Black Higher Education in the Age of Booker T. Washington: A Case Study, 1976; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Case, Suzanne, Eliza Farnham: the Woman and Her Era. Second Place Winner of the James Birdsall Weter Prize 1978/79., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Chestnut, James E., Thomas Starkey: Adiaphora and the Visionary Pragmatist in Pre-Reformation England., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Clark, Timothy C., The Oregon Grange and Public Power, 1930-1940., June 1972 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Fred H., The Limits of Corporate Power - The Origins of the National Recovery Act: A Case Study (Princeton University), 1972; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cohen, Fred, The Origins of the New American Empire: A Study of the Political Economy of American Foreign Policy Planning From 1940 to 1945 for the Post-WWII Years, 1970; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Collins, Bruce, Rioting and Social Upheaval: Philadelphia, 1830-1850., August 1975 (Box 1)
  - Coox, Roy, The Lion of Flanders Awakens: The Flemish Movement from Caesar to Baudouin., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Croll, John D., Development of the Canadian Expeditionary Force during the First World War, 1914-1918., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Cureton, Stewart, Jr., California: The Statemaking Process., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Dement, Thomas E., The Nazis in Austria: 1933-1934., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Deverell, William Francis, Jr., Of Chief and Other Factors: Great Britain and the Surrender of Oregon in 1846., May 1983 (Box 1)
  - Dunn, Darlene Sue, Women, Sainthood, and Medieval Society, 1000-1500. Recipient of 2nd prize, James Birdall Weter Prize for Outstanding Senior Honors Paper, 1978. (Box 1)
  - Feldstein, Tom, As One War Ends Another Begins, 1977; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ferguson, Tim W., Robert A. Taft: Politics and His Many Principles, 1977; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Frakes, James B., A Comparison of Strategies Used by Edward III and Henry B in the Hundred Years War., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Friedlander, Pete, Ideology and methodology: Richard Hofstadter from The American Political Tradition to The Age of Reform. (Box 1)
  - Friedlander, Pete, Ideology and Methodology: Richard Hofstadter from The American Political Tradition to The Age of Reform, 1969; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Friend, James Hugo, Political and Ideological Anti-Semitism in America and Germany, 1974; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Geier, Bradley A., Opposition literature and the Genesis of the American Revolution. (Box 1)
  - Haddad, Mark, Ecology in France: the Case for Revolution. Recipient of 1st prize, James Birdall Weter Prize for Outstanding Senior Honors Paper. (Box 1)
  - Haller, Uli, A Study of selected Mayan vases. (Box 1)
  - Harrington, Helise H., Indirect Rule and the Development of the Gold Coast Educated Elite., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Harris, John B., United States Foreign Policy and the International Control of Atomic Energy, 1945-1946: The Politics of Power, 1977; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Harris, John B., The United States and the Korean War: The Decision to Intervene, June 25-30, 1950, 1977; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Henner, Leslie, Love and Separation: an Examination of the Enduring Friendship Between Mary Hallock Foote and Helena de Kay Guilder, 1968-1916., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Herman, Debra, Past into Future: Feminists and Historians on Women's History, 1973; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Herman, Mike, The Bases for Modern Protestant Involvement in the Struggle for Social Justice: Reinhold Niebuhr and Robert McAfee Brown, 1975-1976; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hoenig, James, The John Peter Zenger Trial., December 1958 (Box 1)
  - Hovley, Stephen, Isaac Hecker and American Catholicism, 1967; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hubbell, Gina, Leon Battista Alberti: Medieval or Modern? A Consideration of Five Transitional Characteristics., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Hvolboll, Eric, The Property God has Given Me: A Brief and Unfinished Story of the Ortega Family and Their Rancho Huestra Senora del Rufugio, Santa Barbara County., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Ingram, Tim H., Artie Samish: The Secret Boss of California, 1965; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ingram, Timothy H., Arthur H. Samish, 1966; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Marilynn S., Chinese slave prostitution in San Francisco, 1950-1930., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Marcy, Lysander Spooner and the Emergence of Scientific Anarchism., March 1972 (Box 2)
  - Kenny, David C., An Interpretive Survey of Urban Development in the Los Angeles Basin., April 1967 (Box 2)
  - Klaus, David M., Standard Oil Company of New Jersey and American Business Creed, not dated; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Kostoff, Jeff, Henry L. Stimson and the Atomic Bomb: A Study of the Development, Use, and Postwar Issues, 1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lawrence, Mark, The Berlin Wall: Kennedy's Way Out of a Crisis, 1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lee, Anita Diane, A bulwark of liberty: the jury, 1670-1800., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Lirtzman, Harry, US - Latin American Economic Relations in 1945 and 1946, 1977; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Long, Thomas D., Fusion between Populists and Democrats in the Presidential election of 1896., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Lundstrom, Robert A., The Multi-Millionaire Has A Hard Time., March 1972 (Box 2)
  - Marshall, Jonathan, Southeast Asia and US - Japan Relations in 1945 and 1946, 1973; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - McDonald, Brian, An Account and Analysis of The Anthracite Coal Strike of 1902, 1984; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - McEvoy, Art, The Asiatic Exclusion League of San Francisco: Organized Labor and Japanese Immigration, 1900-1914, 1973; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - McManus, Doyle, The United States and Argentina, 1944-1950, 1974; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - McManus, Doyle D., Enemies and Friends: The United States and Fascism, 1944-1952, 1974; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Murdoch, Michael Burris, The "Recognition Myth": A Revisionist Analysis of Civil War International Diplomacy., May 1980 (Box 2)
  - Myhre, William Norwood, The Temperance Movement in the 1830s: A Case Study of the Deerfield Temperance Society., April 1972 (Box 2)
  - O'Donnell, Robert J., Marin County and the Second World War: Industrial Activity and Agricultural Decline., June 1981 (Box 2)
  - Pearson, Mark W., Intervention in Southeast Asia - The Early Decisions of John F. Kennedy, 1984; 1 folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pelesh, Mark L., The Gentleman and the Professional: Whig and Democrat 1832-1856., April 1975 (Box 2)
  - Peterson, Elizabeth, The District Magistrate in Late Imperial China: a Discussion of the Ideal Function and An Historical Case., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Piomelli, Ascanio A., The Eisenhower Administration and Cuba: Fighting Revolution, 1956-1959., 1982; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Richardson, Wendy L., Presidential Crisis Decision-Making: The Cuban Missile Crisis and the American Entry into the Korean War, 1980; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ross, William Dale, The Ghost Dance, the Battle of Wounded Knee and the Sioux. (Box 2)
  - Roth, Randolph, Berkeley Then -- A Preliminary Study of Reform and Radicalism in Berkeley, California: 1851 to 1923, not dated; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Rowen, Hilary Neill, Urban Renewal and the Urban Poor: A Study of Relocation Legislation, 1974; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Russell, Holly Virginia, The Tempered Sword: A Social History of the Duel in France, 1598-1630., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Scheiber, Susan Beth, "A Red Hot Suffrage Campaign": The Woman Suffrage Cause in California, 1896., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Sellers, John H., Idealism, Alliance, and Empire: U.S. Foreign Policy toward British Colonialism in Southeast Asia 1941-1945, 1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Shnell, James H., Political Socialization in Revolutionary Virginia., May 1972 (Box 2)
  - Silber, Ralph, A Historical Perspective on the Development of Health Insurance in Italy, 1865-1943: A Case Study in Interdisciplinary Policy Analysis., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Spitz, Stephen, Southern opposition to the homestead., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Stephens, John W., A Quantitative History of Chinatown, San Francisco, 1870 and 1880, 1974; 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Steuer, David S., Anti-Semitism in Romanian Politics, 1920-1944., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Stevens, David O., German Diplomacy in the Spanish Civil War., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Taft, Tracy Marie, A Study in the Problem Structure of the Philosophy of History in the Enlightenment., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Thompson, Roger R., Strange bedfellows: the Chinese Communist Party and the local elites of North China, 1937-1945., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Thulin, Charles H., Deconcentration of Industry in Germany 1945-1949, 1972; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Tipson, Frederick S., American diplomacy and the food relief, 1918-1919; the beginnings of economic diplomacy., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Towner, Robert L., The Truman Administration and the Chinese Civil War: America's Response to Communism in China, 1949-1950, 1 folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Wallstrom, Timothy Clarke, Reinhold Neibuhr's interpretation of Martin Luther's social ethics., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Walt, Christopher, American Business and European Recovery, 1944-1951, 1972; 1 folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Wysham, John, Keeping the peace: a new look at the Japanese-American War., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Young, Keith, A study in totalitarian diplomacy: the Pact of Steel -- a successful military alliance or a harbinger of military disaster., April 1980 (Box 7)
  - Zachariasen, Kerry, Images of women in the work of Denis Diderot., June 1983 (Box 7)
- Theses, 1992-1996; Accession ARCH-1997-032
  - Adler, Deborah A., Crimes against Women: Lucy Stone and Henry Blackwell's Campaign against Wife-Abuse, 1875-1893., May 15, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Alioto, Lia Rose, Amerian Catholic Responses to the Holocaust during World War II., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Amen, Rob, Nafhu-T-Tib Min Ghosni-L-Andalusi (Frangrant Smell from Tender Shoots of Andalus): Political Culture in the Andalusian and Ottoman Empires., June 7, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Ancar, Katina, Towards a Revolutionary Morality: Marriage, children, and Family in the Black Panther Party., June 8, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Armenteros, Carol, The Emigration of Political Islam: Discourses of Power, Authenticity and Identity Among Egyptian Emigres on the Net., May 17, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Biernoff, Ari, San Francisco Bookstores and the Assembly of a Public Idiom., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Bloom, Melissa, Molding the Air; Herbert Hoover and Radio Broadcast Regulation, 1921-1927., June 4, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Buxton, Eric C., Henry L. Stimson and the Atomic Bomb: Development, Debate, Deliberation, and Decision., June 7, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Carlson, Charles, Re-Representing Japan: Orientalism, Ideology, and Elite Representations of Post-War Japan, 1993; 1 folder(s)
  - Chavez, Roberta Marguerite, Intimate Alliances: Intermarriage Between Mexicans and Anglos in Nineteenth-Century California., June 2, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Chen, Ann H., Economic Theories as Metaphors of Reality: Understanding the New American Laborer in Late Nineteenth Century America., May 22, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Clark, Lisa, The Effects of the Transfer of Louisiana Territory from Franco-Iberian Domination to American Rule on the Free People of Color in New Orleans, 1763-1830., Spring 1995 (Box 2)
  - Couvrette, Stephanie, The Lemon Grove Incident: An Evolution of Hisotrical Meaning and Memory., May 17, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Deshpande, Chitra, Divided Identities: A Case Study of the National Identity of the Sakhalin Korean., Spring 1996 (Box 2)
  - Dorman, Jacob S., Hatzaad Harishon: Integration, Black Power and Black Jews in New York, 1964-1972.., May 1996 (Box 2)
  - Draper, Stark Christiaan, The Conceptualization of an Albanian Nation., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Dworkin, Andy, The Poetry of Sacrifice: Fascism, Agriculture and the Organization of Rural Italy., March 13, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Dyl, Joanna Leslie, "Burn This and Memorize Yourself": The Collectivist Small Group as a Social Movement Organization in Women's Liberation in the Bay Area., May 17, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Easter, Kent W., A Revolutionary in Retirement., June 8, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Edmondson, Dale, The Origins of the Japanese/American Security Relationship., May 17, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Flemma, Thomas J., The Glorious Rescue: The Glover Case and Wisconsin's Nullification in Ableman v. Booth., May 17, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Foster, Victoria Rose, Immigration and the Politics of National Origins Favoritism after the Hart-Cellar Act (1965-1986)., July 1996 (Box 3)
  - Geiger, Anne, From Godmothers to Tourists: American Women in France During World War I., June 1, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Girard, Marion, World War II British Poster Artists: Abram Games and Fougasse., May 13, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Gitin, Robert, The Plight of Street Youth: A Historical Perspective and Contemporary Overview., May 17, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Glenn, Jason Edwin, In Genes We Trust: The Rise of Eugenic Discourse into Medicine and Academia in the Late 19th and Early 20th Centuries., May 1996 (Box 3)
  - Hartmen, Timothy M., The Politics of Spiritual Institutions: A Comparison of the Roman Catholic Church in Poland and the Protestant Church in East Germany, 1978-1989., May 22, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Hesp, Richard R., Ngugi wa Thiong'o: The Evolution of an African Intellectual., May 15, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Hodge, Vincent, Jr., "Revolution From Above" Versus "Revolution From Below": A Microhistorical Analysis of Party Politics in Kaluga Guberniia, 1926-29., June 4, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Hoffman, Andrea, Personal Scandals, Public Men: A Study of Scandal and Politics., May 22, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Inboden, William C. III, Divine Elections: Abortion, Evangelicalism, and the New Right in American Politics, 1973-1980: the Politicization of Morality., May 16, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Joe, Melissa G., Race, Religion, and Reform: White attitudes Toward Blacks in America from Colonial Times to the Early National Period., May 15, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Kallmer, Josh, The Economics of Ostpolitik: West German Perceptions of the East German Economy, 1969-1989., March 21, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Kinsey, Laura L., Images of a Female Monarch: Maria Theresa and Her Search for Legitimacy, 1740-1745., May 1994 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence, Eloise Paul, The ERA and Abortion: The Birth of NOW., December 14, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Christine J., Historical Perspectives for the People Without History: The Coolie trade to Latin America, 1847-1874., May 1995 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Janet, "Confessing Our Sins": Strategies and Rhetoric of southern Child Labor Reformers, 1901-1915., May 22, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Kelly H., Birth, Death, and Resurrection: An Evaluation of the Minority Report of 1909., Spring 1993 (Box 4)
  - Leonard, Andrew, Nationalism in Czech-American Immigrant Communities, 1850-1918., May 14, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Lesky, Justin, Power, Politis, and Radicalism: The San Francisco Labor Council, 1906-1911., May 22, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Lindberg, Matthew Lee, Cultures in Conflict: The origins of the Yakama Indina War of 1855., May 17, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Madar, Chase, Ten Years after Barney Clark: A Recent History of the Artificial Heart., May 17, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Manley, Sharla, Evolution and Economics in "Multicultural" Hawaii., May 17, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Marcus, Becky, Stokely Carmichael/Kwame Toure; The Reconstruction of Identity., May 1992 (Box 5)
  - McMeekin, Sean, From Beaumarchais to Chenier: the droits d'auteur and the Fall of the Comedie Francaise, 1777-1791., May 16, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Michaelsen, Kaarin, Storming the Citadel: British an dAmerican Women's ATtempts to Obtain Medical Education at Harvard and at the University of Edinburgh, 1847-1883., June 5, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Mikkelson, Erika K., Catholic Converts in a Protestant Land: Exploring Religious Conversion in Seventeenth-Century England., May 17, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Moyle, Rebecca, Gender, Sex, and Kinship: An Analysis of Women in the Icelandic Sagas., May 17, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Muttana, Nilima, Refugee Policy in Soviet Occupied Germany., May 17, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Nelson, Benjamin, The Federalist Thought of Two Republicans: A comparison of James Madison and John Taylor of Caroline., Winter 1993 (Box 6)
  - Olson, Anna, "I was a stranger...": Community Identity and the Politics of Welcoming Central Americans at Casa Oscar Romero, 1982-1992., May 17, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Orr, Steve, Conspiracy Ideas and the Revolutionary Political Imagination after Thermidor: The Tragedy of Francois-Victor Aigoin., Spring 1996 (Box 6)
  - Penick, Monica, Reinventing the Past: Ideology and Meaning in Twelfth-Century British Legendary Histories., Spring 1996 (Box 6)
  - Pinto, Ashok Michael, Man in the Middle: South Asians in East Africa. An analysis focusing on the Asian expulsion from Uganda in 1973. (Box 6)
  - Racine, Aaron J., Christianity in Roman and Sub-Roman Britain, 250-550 A.D., June 4, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Ratnesar, Romesh, On the road to the Cold War: Western Diplomacy, National Security, and the Communist Coup in Czechoslovakia, 1948., May 17, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Robison, Peter, The Russian Far East, Today and Tomorrow: Prospects for Economic Development., May 27, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Scarlett, Philippa Milane, The German "Jewish Question" and the American "Negro Problem": Where Racism, Nationalism and Lilberalism Intersect., May 17, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Schnabel, Frederick, An Essay in Leveller Democracy., June 6, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Schwindt, Karin A., The Igbo Women's War: Women and Colonialism in Southeastern Nigeria., May 10, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Scott, Michelle Renee, Jazz: The "Mule of Music" or "An Expression of Negro Life"? African American Intellectual Reactions to Jazz, 1920-1930., May 17, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Setty, Sudha, A Program for Revolution: The Philosophy and Work of the Reverend James M. Lawson, Jr., within the African-American Civil Rights Movement., May 22, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Shah, Mariah S., The Use of Film on the American Home Front: The Why We Fight Series and the Films of Preston Sturges., May 13, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Shue, Allison, An Assembly Line Left Behind: The Decline of Manufacturing, Black Auto Workers, and Socioeconomic Disparity in Detroit, Michigan., May 17, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Sladden, Chloe Rebecca, Redesigning Identity, Exploring Citizenship: The New Zealand Women's Suffrage Movement., May 17, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Snekvik, Andrew, Historiographic Trends in Russian History After World War II in America: Karpovich, Berlin and the Harvard Group., May 22, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Sondik, Karen, The Nebi Musa Riot, Jerusalem, April, 1920: An Introduction to the Palin Report., May 16, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Stasinos, John, An Exploration of Nationalism: The Military Class of the Greek Revolution of 1821-1827., May 17, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Sun, Tammy Wei-Ling, "Not Only a Women's Cause": Men in the British Suffrage Movement, 1907-1914., May, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Suri, Jeremi, America's Search for a Technological Solution to the Arms Race: Eisenhower and the Surprise Attack Conference of 1958., May, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Teodorescu, Gabriela, King Carol II and the Front for National Rebirth: Nationalism and National Defense in Pre-World War II Romania., May 17, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Trotter, Tiffany D., Revising History: The Life of Bayard Rustin in Conjunction with the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Challenge of 1964., June, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Turner, David A., The "Hedgers," Aristocratic Independence, and the House of Lords Crisis of 1911., May 31, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Tyson, Dylan, Pitfalls of Popular Perception: The Mistaken Allure of Supply-Reduction Efforts in the Reagan/Bush Era., May 22, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Valim, Molly Ellen, Female Draft Exclusion in America: The Emergence of a Political Controversy that Facilitated the Defeat of the ERA., May 22, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Walsh, Nicholas, "The Worst of Crimes is Poverty": Veterans and Crime in Britain, 1815-1820., May, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Wan, Christine D., Redefining the Patriarch's Wife: An Exploration of the Compatibility of Patriarchal Political Theory with Seventeenth-Century Proto-Feminism., May 17, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Watkins, Norman, No Epsom nor Ascot! Henry James and the American Artist., May 15, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Watts, Tamara, Women, Gender and Trade Unions: Jennie Matyas and the San Francisco International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1934-1941., May 17, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Wayland, Karen, Grappling with Convictions: The Attitudes Behind the Actions of Munich Historian Karl Alexander Von Muller (1882-1964)., 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Weaver, Heather Ann, Dear Child: Children's Literature in Seventeenth-Century England., March, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Woods, Jeremy, Journalistic Style and Political Coverage: Time Magazine's Images of Nazism, 1933-1939., June 2, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Yahil, Edna Ruth, O venerabilis domina et mater Karissima! Remembering the Saintly Queen Mathilda, 919-1024., May 22, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Yoo, Charles, Utopia: Protestant Utopias of the 16th Century, American Utopias of the 19th Century and Technopia of the 30th Century., May 14, 1993 (Box 9)
- Theses, 1997; Accession ARCH-1997-136
  - Boegle, Jimmy, Mormons Divided: the Emergence of Two Mormon Churches Following the Death of Joseph Smith., May 16, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Ezer, Tamar, A Distorted Mirror: French Chinoiserie in the Age of Enlightenment., May 1997 (Box 1)
  - Flechner, Lawrence, Imagining a Jewish Army: The Impact of the Jewish Legion on Anglo Jewry., May 16, 1997 (Box 1)